## PERSONAL INFORMATION

Full name LU HONG HAI

Date of birth: March 17th, 1988

Nationality: Vietnam

Email: <a href="mailto:luhonghai@gmail.com">luhonghai@gmail.com</a>

Personal website: <a href="http://luhonghai.info">http://luhonghai.info</a>

Linkedin: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/luhonghai">https://www.linkedin.com/in/luhonghai</a>

Telephone: +84 (0) 986 899 787

Address: No.39 429 Kim Ma, Ba Dinh, Ha Noi

Current Occupation: Technical Lead



# **BRIEF INFORMATION**

Broad understanding and in-depth experience in architecture design for both frontend and backend. Strong at object-oriented programming (OOP) and DevOps.

Database design, API design and development. Focus to microservices architecture, auto scaling and load balancing by using Kubernetes and Docker.

Wise knowledge in mobile development, Android is primary. Have experience with React Native as well.

Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery for both frontend and backend.

Cloud computing with Azure and Amazon Web Service.

Interested in big data, machine learning, blockchain, decentralized applications development (Ethereum, EOS).

Good command of English.

Strong in researching, analyzing, presentation, documentation, training and teamwork skills.

# **EDUCATION**

2006 – 2011 Hanoi University of Science and Technology Hanoi, Vietnam

Faculty of Mathematics and Computer Science

2009 – 2013 FPT Aptech Hanoi, Vietnam

Software Engineering

#### **SKILLS**

Issue tracking: Atlassian Jira.

DevOps Kubernetes, Docker, Fastlane, NSQ, ELK, Graphite, Sentry ...

Framework Django, React Native, React JS

Continuous Integration: Jenkins (primary), Atlassian Bamboo, Hudson, Travis.

Version control: Git (primary), SVN.

Operate system: Mac OS X (primary), Linux, Windows.

Programing language: Java, Javascript (ES6), Python.

Database: MySQL, MSSQL, Oracle, SQLite, Realm, MongoDB.

#### **WORKING EXPERIENCES**

2016 - Present Mobile Health Vietnam Hanoi, Vietnam

Position: Technical Lead

Job Description: - Architecture design

- Code review for both mobile and backend

- API development

- DevOps , setup CI & CD by using Jenkins, Fastlane, Fabric, Docker,

Kubernetes

- R&D, estimation, documentation, training ...

2015 - 2016 Claybourne McGregor (C-MG) Hanoi, Vietnam

Position: Senior Developer

Job Description: Lead, design, develop and maintain accenteasy® Administration server,

accenteasy® Android and accenteasy® iOS application.

Training fresher Android and iOS developer.

2011 - 2014 Claybourne McGregor (C-MG) Hanoi, Vietnam

Position: Developer

Job Description: Maintain BP Pensionline system and develop new system for BP from the

beginning of 2012 called BP Pablo.

Lead, develop and maintain a training requirements mapping automation

tool for BP Upstream.

Write document, setup and guide team to apply Continuous Integration process, move from SVN to Git, upgrade Issus tracking system and build

tool (Jira, Bamboo, Github).

Investigate and apply Amazon Web Service, Machine learning, Digital signal processing for pronunciation application called accenteasy®.

Work on some projects use Google Cloud Computing (Google App

Engine), Android and iOS application.

#### **ATTENDED PROJECTS**

2016 - Present Mobile Health, MaNaDr Platform

Project URL: <a href="https://www.manadr.com/">https://www.manadr.com/</a>

Position: Technical Lead

Responsibilities: - Architecture design

- Code review for both mobile and backend

- DevOps

- API development

Project description Mobile Health is pioneering a massive healthcare ecosystem by

integrating businesses, professionals and individuals across the entire healthcare space. Best known as the healthcare technology company and

operator of the MaNaDr platform, Mobile Health aims to provide:
- A trusted healthcare platform for each patient for life; and

- A revolutionary healthcare business platform for doctors, practice and

providers etc.

Programming languages: Python, Java, Go lang, Javascript

Technologies: Azure, Android, iOS, Django, React JS, Kubernetes, Docker, NSQ, ELK,

Graphite, Sentry

2011 - 2012 CMG Future Monitor™

Project URL: <a href="http://monitor.c-mg.com">http://monitor.c-mg.com</a>

Position: Developer

Responsibilities: - Development

- Deployment

Project description The "Future Monitor™" works by constantly monitoring reports running on

multiple servers, which it collates into a central server to check and compare their health. Each server runs a number of local health checks

and provides advance warning, through an alert to the systems

operations team, if the server appears to be underperforming. A unique characteristic of this system is it does not inundate you with alerts, but intelligently notifies you only when a key threshold is met or an event has

changed status.

Programming languages: Java

Technologies: Google App Engine, JPA, JDO, Memcache, Maven

2012 - 2015 BP PensionLine - Self-Service Financials

Client: BP Pension

Project URL: <a href="https://pensionline.bp.com">https://pensionline.bp.com</a>

Position: Developer

Responsibilities: - Maintain and fix bugs.

- Develop new feature

- Improve build script and process

- Report development status to manager

Project description:

BP Pensionline is a feature rich site that allows over 60,000 members to manage their contributions in a secure self-service environment. It is worth well over £13.8 billion GB Pounds.

Specifically responsible for the following tasks:

Rewriting Sarbanes Oxley (SOX) compliant security and login module.
 Business continuity plan – regression, load and penetration testing as

well as backup.

- Financial calculation fixes and adjustments to Aquila's financial calculations.
- Business requirements gathering and documentation, RUP methodology.
- Development of Model View Controller (MVC), JSPs and flow handlers into a "skin-able" site.
- Advise on Data Protection Act and user demographics.
- Development of demographics gathering and report generation via WebTrends and data-mining.
- Financial payslips forecasts, implementing A-day tax calculations.
- Automated PDF generation of on-line documents from data held in database via XSLT and FOML.
- Reporting to risk and review committee.
- Automated test regression harness for financial calculations

Programming languages: Java, HTML, Javascript, CSS, SQL

Technologies: OpenCMS, ISAPI, JBoss AS, MSSQL Server, Ant

2012 - 2015 BP Pablo

Client: BP Pension

Project URL: <a href="https://plw1-prd.bppensions.com/pablo/content">https://plw1-prd.bppensions.com/pablo/content</a>

Position: Developer

Responsibilities: - Develop

- Maintain and fix bugs.

- Improve build script and process

- Report development status to manager

Project description: BP Pensionline requires an internal Continent Management System,

project name: Pablo. The system has to have BP branding and security.

Programming languages: Java, HTML, Javascript, CSS, SQL

Technologies: OpenCMS, ISAPI, Tomcat, MSSQL Server, Ant

Jan 2013 BP Pensionline Mobile: Newsletter

Client: BP Pension

Project URL: Google Play

App store

Position: Team leader / Developer

Responsibilities: - Research framework, tools and API

Design architecture, create development planCreate project structure, automation build script

DevelopDistributeVersion control

- Report development status to manager

Project description: Newsletter - PDF reader that lets user list, download and read newsletters

from Pensionline system.

Programming languages: Java, Objective-C

Technologies: Android, iOS, Maven

#### Dec 2013 BP Upstream - training requirements mapping automation tool

Client: BP Upstream

Position: Team leader / Developer

Responsibilities: - Create development plan

- Create project structure, automation build script

DevelopDeliver

- Version control

- Report development status to manager

Project description: Working with lead consultants from Accenture and Harvey Nash to

disseminate their process to automate mapping 5,000 contractors and employees to specialisms in upstream (Azerbaijan, Gulf of Mexico & North

Sea).

The tool selects various methods to map the users to their specialisms and plugs the ETL integration issues from their HR SAP, LDAP (MS Active

Server) data.

Programming languages: VBA, SQL

Technologies: MS Access, MSSQL Server

### Aug 2014 accenteasy®

Project URL: <a href="http://www.accenteasy.com">http://www.accenteasy.com</a>

Google Play App store

Position: Team leader / Senior Developer

Responsibilities: - Research technology, tools and API

Design architecture, create development planCreate project structure, automation build script

DevelopDistributeVersion control

- Report development status to manager

Project description:

Machine learning and natural language processing (NLP) company accenteasy shared their expertise with Education Ministers on their 2020 English language project. The aim of Project 2020 is to improve English language standards in Singapore, Malaysia and Vietnam by 2020.

Accenteasy built a tool to harvest words spoken with a British (RP) accent and used deep learning to classify features in the digital signals of these words. Machine learning was used to develop the ultimate version, which can identify when speakers veer away from the RP accent.

Personally responsible for:

- consulting on machine learning techniques
- designing algorithms to analyze pitch, power and pace
- meetings with Education Ministers in Vietnam and UK Trade and Industry
- establishing a team of linguists and deep learning experts in Singapore and Vietnam
- strategy for delivering access to back-end through SaaS
- edutech to harvest data-sets to train machine learning models and proving statistical accuracy

Programming languages: Java, Swift, Python, HTML, CSS, SQL

Technologies: Android, iOS, Digital signal processing, Machine learning, Google

Tensorflow, Load balancing, Auto Scaling, Amazon Web Services, JPA,

JDO, Datanucleus, MySQL, Maven, Gradle.

Technologies: Android, JNI, RTMP protocol, PHP

#### **TECHNICAL EXPERTISE**

	1	2	3	4	5
Experiences:	1 - 6 months	6 - 12 months	1 – 2 years	2 – 5 year	> 5 years
Grade:	Weak	Fair	Average	Good	Expert

Skills	Experiences	Grade
Development plan	5	5
Architecture design	5	5
Agile, Scrum	5	5
Continuous integration & Continuous Delivery	5	5
Web development	5	5
Android development	5	5
Backend & DevOps	5	5

Kubernetes	3	4
Docker	3	4
Java	5	5
Javascript (ES6)	5	5
Database / SQL	4	5
Python	4	4
Django	4	4
React Native	3	4
React JS	3	4
Git	5	5

# **FOREIGN LANGUAGE**

	1	2	3	4	5
Expert level	Beginner	Conversational	Fluent	Expert	Translator

Language	Listening	Speaking	Reading	Writing
English	3	3	4	4